Gabriel said, what usually happens in the conversation
after you present the cost
and do you deal with the elephant in the room?
Tension of them wondering what the price is this whole time?
So Gabriel, you've been here
for the past couple days, right?
What did I tell you? They already know it costs, right?
Because I'm telling them on the discovery call,
they see it on our website.
They know the ballpark of what they're getting, right?
I don't, I don't get to this point.
I like, you know, how much work that takes?
That's about three hours worth
of Annette's time when she's humming and optimized.
That costs me money as a business and time
and resources so that this doesn't get pre built
unless they know a ballpark.
You know, ballpark is pretty accurate, right?
Like I know looking at a,
I don't even need to go through the analysis.
I talk about like, oh, I need those scope.
Like I can look at your homepage
and spend five minutes on your website and kind of know,
and maybe like two minutes in hres
and pretty much know what I'm gonna charge you.
You know? And if you've been doing this once you,
if you don't have a ton of experience with it,
then you know, you'll figure out that process too.
But that just comes with time and experience.
Time on task is, the more you do these,
the more you're gonna walk into these ahead of time knowing
and you just gotta communicate that ahead of time.
And just in terms of like, it's maybe,
maybe if I'm reading too much into this,
but it sounds like maybe you're a little bit uncomfortable
giving them the pricing, right?
You want to do it face-to-face.
You wanna do it face-to-face.
You don't wanna send anything to them that has anything
to do with money and allow them the opportunity to come
to their own conclusions
and to react with a amongst themselves.
'cause like, yeah, I mean 11,000 for that.
They're, that law firm is currently paying like 25,000.
So 11,000 is like nothing for what they're currently paying.
Have access inside information on that. That's how I know.
But like I want to tell them face to face.
'cause I want to see the look on their face when I tell them
and I show them that and I want to hear their energy
so I can address it, right?
So if they're like, then I'm like, okay, let's,
let's talk like, let's talk about the pricing.
You know, like if tell I, I'll ask them the question.
I'll say, tell me where that lands, right?
Does this number come in, in range?
Is this something that you're, you're good with?
Is this I'll, I'll ask them
and I want to have that conversation about it, right?
So like the elephant in the room,
Gabriel can be a little bit uncomfortable for sure,
but like when we do that, we just wanna re-anchor
that against expected results.
So I'll say if that, if that $11,000 came back
and they were like, yeah, this is, this is a lot of money.
I would say I agree $11,000 is a lot of money.
And I'll be even more honest.
Be like, especially 'cause of the fact that like,
you're not gonna see a return in a
couple within a couple of months.
Like this is a long term thing.
And I say, but let's go back
and look at the, the value
of the traffic that you're gonna get from this.
Your competitors getting $268,000 a month of traffic, right?
What will that do to your PPCC bill?
Like how much money are you gonna save on your PPC bill?
Number one or two, how much,
how much value you're gonna gain from that.
That's Google telling you what this traffic is worth.
I'm charging you one 20th of that to get you optimized.
And this stuff grows in perpetuity over time.
The more that's compounds, the more that you're gonna see,
the more that you're gonna grow,
the more calls you're gonna get.
What's the value of phone call to you? Right?
What's, and I'll ask them too, like,
what's the value of a client to you?
And they'll be like, I don't know, $20,000.
So I'll be like, you need to tell me that if I can't get,
like I only need to get you one client a month for you
to break even and even be profitable on this
and this feels like it's too much for you.
Right? So like we just wanna put it back on them
and have them be like, yeah, no, you're right.
You're right. Like nobody's, nobody's gonna say no to that.
And that's the, the beauty of doing personal injury SEO is I
know what their clients are worth to them
and the value that this brings.
So I, I'll be like, dude, we're undercharging.
Like, you know how much work it takes to do this?
You know what my bills look like.
You know what my margins look like.
They're not what yours are. Trust me.
So you want to address it with them,
Gabriel, don't shy away from it.
Don't be uncomfortable about it.
You know, I say this about salespeople all the time.
To me the most important skill a salesperson can have is
being comfortable making people uncomfortable.
And that pricing is one of those things
and calling them is another thing, right?
So those are big things. Sean said,
have you ever had a lawyer who has worked
with multiple marketing agencies ask you
for the proposal break down exactly what you're gonna do?
My concern is they're gonna go, I don't
to their current agency send the
analysis without becoming a client.
I tell 'em all the time to take it. You know why?
Because I tell 'em that if their agency needs this
information to do it, then they're not worth,
they can't lick my boots.
This is, I tell them I do this to you for free.
Imagine what we do for if you actually paid us, right?
I give in guys, I give in everything away for free.
You go to my YouTube channel for years,
how much stuff I be giving away for free to agencies.
How many agencies actually implement this stuff?
People pay to come here in the blueprint training
and they don't implement what I tell them to do.
Information's free man.
Like I know it takes time and resources,
but like the goodwill
and equity that you put out, that
that is a scarcity mindset, Sean,
that like you need a break man.
You know, like if people are stealing this work like cool,
they need it more than you do.
You know? So don't worry about that. Do your job.
Your job is to do the best possible thing
that you can for your clients.
If you want to pass per,
like you said, I just saw the second question.
If you want password protected, absolutely you can do that.
You can just share the Google doc with just them.
You can revoke access afterwards, right?
You can just share it with them and then
revoke access after a week.
All those types of things. But man, like take it from me.
People still work. That's what agencies do.
There's really like spending too much time
and energy worrying about that.
Not get used to your time. I'd rather spend having you spend
more time being like, yo, this is really dope
what Ryan put together, but how can I make this,
how can I make dentists prospects
excited to show up to this call?
Right? How can I give them so much value
that they can't wait to work with me?
You know? So I mean maybe Sean that comes off condescending.
'cause I'm so used to it. Like I,
I gave a 10 minute preamble here about
how you shouldn't just steal this verbatim,
but like I know people are gonna steal verbatim period
after I spent 10 minutes talking about it.
It is what it is. So we control, we control
and don't spend too much time
worrying about the things that you can't control.
Because your job is to do the best possible thing
for your clients and prospects.
And I know you do. So Marin asked,
how do you measure the value of your work?
We'll bring in in terms of money if we don't deal
with clients where they don't have booking system
and we can't directly tie
them out, they're getting for bookings.
And is SEO only about bookings
or get more visibility and future potential?
Bring this, so Marin, we track everything man.
We tie, we tie everything directly into the client's CRM
so they can see all the leads
that are coming from anything from an organic source.
If they're not doing that, then like that is a problem with
who you're pitching, right?
And that might be something
that you wanna start putting into your offer
about doing that for them.
Because like, nobody's gonna pay you
Top dollar for marketing
if they don't know what they're making.
Like if you're, if you're, if you're consistently dealing
with prospects
or clients who don't have any sort of mechanism to track,
not even like analytics tracking,
but like what are they doing with the leads or the sale?
Like if they're not generating sales,
right, they're generating leads.
Those are the two, basically
only two business models, right?
Generating direct revenue is easy to track.
It's tracked in analytics generating leads like are,
if they're just like letting leads go to email
and they're like, yeah, we got more.
Like they are not a qualified business
to be working with you at that time.
'cause they're never gonna, like they,
they're never gonna pay you what you deserve
because they don't even know what they're making off you
and it's kind of irresponsible for them, right?
So again, if that's something,
and I get it like some businesses are like that,
like home services are like, dude, I don't know,
like people call my phone and I pick up
and I, I make what I make.
You know, so when dealing with clients like that,
like you've got to make sure that they have some sort
of tracking mechanism set up really for their own good.
Because otherwise you're never gonna get paid
what you deserve to be paid on those for those clients.
So something to consider about your service
and your offer about adding that in potentially.
Adrian asked, in your experience, what's the best way
of finding SEO specialists to do this sort
of analysis and what would be the pay range?
I would say Upwork would be good for this to me, like kind
of an offshore SEO specialist is
good for this, I'll tell you that.
We pay a net $3,000 a month
and then I give her a very small percentage on deals closed.
And that was about in range
what she was making the base a little bit
less than what she was making before.
But you know, she makes, she makes pretty good money now
'cause we've closed deals and she gets
paid for recurring off of these.
I think it's like a one or 2% rip off
of whatever clothes that she works on.
So you know, like it's important
that you're not hiring a sales specialist,
you're hiring an SEO specialist
and you've got this training to run them through
and you should be training them heavily
on that stuff as well.
Andreas asked, on a scale of one to five,
how important are the GA 4G SC insights in your audits?
Most of the time it's hard to get access.
We don't know, is it, we don't do it.
You didn't hear me talk about that one time in here.
We don't get access to analytics,
search console, none of that stuff.
I agree it slows down the process
and like this stuff needs to get done fast
and like we're not going back and forth
and like, here's a video and how to do it
and then two weeks later they're like, it's a pain.
I, it's just too much. So we don't do it.
I mean if we're doing PPC then we will need
to get ads access so we can audit their current performance.
But like you don't really need it for SEO.
I mean, would it be helpful? Sure, absolutely.
But like Arus does a good enough job to get, I mean you saw
that was a 40 page deck, you know,
like you can definitely make it more in depth if you're
getting actual access to the analytics.
But for these types of pitches, if it's like a,
a much larger pitch for sure,
but like, yeah, we're not, we're not,
we're not wasting time on that.
I agree. It's, it's too much chasing back and forth.
That's like a pet peeve of mine.
Sean said, we always get asked
how long does it take for this to work?
When do I get a return? And how much in return,
how do you manage those questions?
Well the traffic protection
tool's really good for that, Sean.
But you can also just kind of build out your own chart
and timeline based on historic results, right?
So like you should look at your client portfolio
and build your own like 12 month graph chart that shows
I have it done for Facebook ads
but not for SEO And we don't
really get asked that question too much.
I don't know why. But for the most part it's just a graph
of like, you know, one to three months percentage growth
and you can put like a chart behind
it, like a graph behind it too.
Like three to six month percentage, nine to three
to like just showing them you,
you just wanna focus on traffic growth
and then you can say, you know,
based on your website's concurrent conversion rate,
X percent more traffic will deliver times 2% in leads.
Right? Whatever, whatever that that looks like.
Yeah, I would just come ready to talk with that Sean.
Like just build a slide for that in your presentation and.